SIENA LOPRINZI, M.A.

sloprinzi@yahoo.com



Alexandria, Virginia, USA

After completing my first Master's degree in Positive Psychology, specializing in resilience and post-traumatic growth in Indigenous communities, I currently focus on data analysis and migration research in my second Masters in Intercultural and International Communications at American University. With a drive for creating interventions for social-cohesion and justice in conflict areas, my goal is to combine international Positive Psychology and data analysis to fight global inequalities.

EDUCATION & RECOGNITIONS

MASTER OF INTERCULTURAL & INTERNATIONAL COMMUNICATIONS/CONCENTRATION ON GLOBAL EQUITY & INCLUSION

American University | 2021-Present

 Completed skill workshops in Intercultural Conflict/Communication and Designing Intercultural Training Programs

MASTER OF APPLIED POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY, 4.0

University of Pennsylvania | 2020 - 2021

- Commissioned for a project by Wharton People Analytics's review of the Wharton School of Business
- Presented Master's Thesis on how <u>Indigenous Storytelling leads to Resilience</u> at the annual Positive Psychology Conference
- Submitted a program curriculum for Suicidal Ideation & Meditation for review at suicide prevention centers

BACHELORS OF INTERNATIONAL STUDIES/BUSINESS MINOR, 3.98 SUMMA CUM LAUDE

Portland State University Honor's College | 2015 - 2017

- Undergraduate <u>Honor's Thesis on Refugee Policies within the UN and EU</u> has over 1,300 downloads
- Peer Mentor | January 2016 June 2017
 - Selected as one of five mentors from a candidate pool of 300+ into part of the prestigious University
 Studies program
 - Mentored 36 culturally diverse college students during their first year at PSU
 - · Developed curriculum alongside a professor to assist students in their integration to college life
 - Taught own curriculum for three 50-minute class periods a week in conjunction to the professor's main class
 - Received 100% tuition reimbursement as a peer mentor

DATA ANALYSIS SKILLS & COURSEWORK

- Software: R studio, Google Sheets, Excel
- Git Hub: sloprinzi
- Coursework: Statistics, Data Analysis
- Data Modeling: regressions

- Data Visualizations: ggplot, patchwork, knitr, table extra, scales in R Studio
- Data Wrangling: reshaping, merging, appending, cleaning

WORK EXPERIENCE

MEDITATION FACILITATOR & BUSINESS OWNER

Siena Wellness | January 2020 - Present

- Guide and facilitate weekly meditations for law firms, international entrepreneurial groups, and organizations for athletes like the American Ballet Theatre in New York
- Certified Mindfulness Facilitator through UCLA's Mindful Awareness Research Center

PROGRAMS INTERNAL COORDINATOR, MEDITATION RETREATS

Drala Mountain Center in Red Feather Lakes, CO | October 2019 - Present

- Organizing and coordinating two week to month-long meditation programs for 15-36 participants in a remote location
- Managing daily team meetings of six staff members
- Leading online Zoom mediation retreats from June 2020 June 2022

BRAIN INJURY YOGA INSTRUCTOR

Love Your Brain, Online | October 2019 - Present

- Teaching the Love Your Brain yoga program for those who have had a brain injury and their caregivers
- · Instructing varied levels of yoga specifically focusing on healing brain trauma
- Creating curriculum for the TBI community

YOGA INSTRUCTOR

Yoga Bhoga and North Portland Yoga in Portland, OR | September 2018 - November 2021

- Teaching 60, 75 and 90 minute Yin, Hatha and Vinyasa Yoga classes, specifically for healing through meditation
- Experienced in teaching all class sizes, abilities and ages

AREA MANAGER

Amazon in Patterson, CA | July 2017 - December 2017

- Led and developed a team of over 30 Amazon associates in a fulfilment center
- · Organized and coordinated shifts for associates and ensured job performance and engagement
- · Focused on motivating, mentoring, and coaching the team to ensure their success

LANGUAGES

- English Native
- Italian Beginner

CERTIFICATES

- In training to become a Registered Herbalist
- Healing Touch Practitioner
- 300 Hr Ayurveda Yoga Therapist
- 500 Hr YA Certified Yoga Teacher
- Red Cross CPR Certified
- · Reiki Master

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- VP of Volunteers at the International Economic Justice League (Newport Beach, CA)
- Children's Book Bank (Portland, OR)
- St. Jude Research Hospital (Memphis, TN)
- Memphis Humane Society (Memphis, TN)
- Oregon Food Bank (Portland, OR)
- ESL tutor (Portland, OR)

INTERESTS

- Tibetan Buddhist practices
 - Traveled with Buddhist monks in Nepal and Bhutan
 - Participated in month-long silent meditation retreats
- Italian and Sicilian culture
 - Italian citizen
 - Lived and studied in Italy in 2016
- Indigenous land practices and intersectional environmentalism
- Reading 70+ books a year
- Traveling 35 countries and counting